I've been using the iron bull 7 mm knee
sleeves for the past few weeks my
favorite things about them are the
double Stitch Contour design it's going
to lie you to stay pretty mobile
throughout your workouts they're 7 mm
thick so it's going to provide a high
level of compression for your workouts
and they're available in five different
sizes from small to double XL if you're
looking for some new knee sleeves to
toss into your gym bag for your workouts
might have just found your fit let's get
into this
[Music]
review
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I've got a pair of 7 mm knee
sleeves from Iron Bull in this video
today we're going to talk about a lot of
stuff but specifically we're going to
talk about some money some pros and cons
you might run into with these knee
sleeves and then of course who should or
maybe should not make this purchase
before I do that though if you're not
aware we've reviewed a whole lot of
other knee sleeves on barbin decom and
we went ahead and made a best list of
all of our top picks so if you want to
check that out all you got to do is
search barbend best knee sleeves it's
going to pull right up for
[Music]
you so before I start really diving into
the pros and the Cons with these knee
sleeves why would you want to wear knee
sleeves all right so the main reason
here is that they're going to add more
warmth and then obviously compression
you know for your knees which can lead
to you know better blood flow and allow
you to you know be more stable within
your workouts and that can also help
with your Technique that compression can
help keep your knee aligned basically
and also you know reduce pain and
discomfort in your knees you know if you
kind of experience that now knee sleeves
are very different from knee wraps okay
so think of a knee wrap exactly as like
a wrist wrap so you're literally
wrapping it around your knee now you you
can get you know a tighter compression
with those you know a tighter fit but
knee sleeves are more practical they
cost more money but they're more
practical you don't have to rely on
somebody else to help you you know get a
secure fit anything like that but with
knee sleeves there's various types right
so once again these are 7 mm thick they
make 5 mm thick sleeves and 3 mm sleeves
which ones do you go with right also
another thing here is remember these are
contoured they also have straight
stitching so which ones do you go with
okay so start with the 3 mm that's going
to be great for anybody who's doing
CrossFit you know Olympic weightlifting
anything like that you need to be really
explosive and and really really mobile
and you're just looking for something
you know to kind of just keep your knees
warm as you're working out 5 millim kind
of in that same you know realm of things
I guess you could say but obviously two
more millimeters of thickness it's going
to provide you know a little bit more
stability now 7 mm that is you know
where the powerlifting really really
comes into play squatting mainly so like
I said powerlifters that's what you want
and so this Contour design compared to a
straight stitch design is going to allow
you to be more mobile within your knees
within your workout so that straight
Stitch that's going to be you know ideal
for people who are really just looking
for some these sleeves for squatting
this Contour design is going to allow
you to you know use them across multiple
lifts maybe you do want to sprinkle in
some Olympic weightlifting maybe you do
want to sprinkle in some Crossfit
workouts whatever it is and then you
know continue to do your powerlifting
that's where that contoured stitching
comes into play so let's talk about some
pros and cons here and I really do like
this contoured stitching it's going to
allow me to use these across all of my
lifts I think that's a really cool thing
remember there are five different sizes
from small to double XL so there's an
option for pretty much every single
athlete out there there's seven
different colorways I think that's cool
you know if you want your accessories to
match your your attire your workout gear
that's going to be really cool too
really cool as well for you now also
really like how there's this little bit
of a rubbery you know grip right here on
the top not every single knee sleeve has
that and that really comes in handy
because if you never worn knee sleeves
you know like I said they're going to
keep your knees warm but that also is
going to lead to you sweating especially
if you sweat already so that extra grip
is going to be really nice you know it's
going to prevent them from sliding down
as you're working out I also think it's
really cool how these are certified by
all these federations right here so if
you're a competitor you can use them you
know when it comes to competition day
with the cons really for me it just
boils down to personal preference you
know I talked about the different styles
of knee sleeves maybe these aren't for
you maybe you want a thinner one maybe
you want you know that straight
stitching so that's it it really just
kind of boils down to what style of
lifting that you're
[Music]
prioritizing all right so these knee
sleeves are going to cost you right
around $60 bucks that's a really solid
deal to me because yeah they're high
quality you know that high quality
neoprene they're also going to last you
I would say at least a year now it's
going to you know be determined by how
often you use them and everything I
think you know about a year I think
that's you know a pretty solid you know
U estimate I guess you could say for how
long they're going to last you
now I'd mentioned that these are more
expensive than knee wraps they're about
twice as expensive and I'm specifically
referring to you iron Bulls they they
have their own knee wraps those are
going to cost you 30 bucks but they're
not as practical as knee sleeves so I
think that you know extra money is is
well worth it now if you compare the
price of these to a company like Rogue
they're cheaper so with Rogue you're
spending 75 bucks you know and that's
$15 you know whatever but 60 bucks you
know anyways this is about the average
price tag now if say say you don't want
this Contour design you want that
straight stitching that I was talking
about you know ironbull also has their
premium sleeve leaves do in fact have
straight stitching those are going to
cost you about 90 95 bucks so honestly
it really just depends on what you're
looking for I think 60 bucks for these
and how versatile they could be for you
is you know worth that price
tag so remember with these sleeves
they're available in five different
sizes from small to dou XL I'll explain
that in further detail in just a second
but also remember these are available in
seven different colors and yes you know
still going to stay black right here
but you know the accents change right so
the stitching and the logo on the front
that's going to change color so you know
might be kind of cool you know just kind
of check it out maybe you can you know
match your Gym gear your tire if that's
something that you're interested in said
it about 15 times we need to get a
little tracker in the bottom corner when
I repeat things like this these are 7 mm
thick don't forget it so it's going to
offer you know really high you know
level of compression but because they
are contoured with that stitching it's
going to allow you to stay pretty mobile
within your knees
[Music]
okay so I've got a pair of medium knee
sleeves right here and it's going to
show you right here on on the inside
right there it's a medium so whenever
you go to do your sizing remember you
want to extend your leg and do it around
your kneecap but you want to make sure
that you have one of those fabric you
know tape measures don't use your
classic one CU it's not going to bend
the right way it's not going to give you
you know that accurate reading and I
also mentioned this earlier sometimes it
helps to go down a size from what you
actually measure you know compared to
the sizing chart because you really want
you know a snug fit with some knee SE
all right so let's just go and
demonstrate you know how to properly put
these on so what I like to do I like
flipping them inside out and you're
going to put it on upside down if that
makes sense it all makes sense whenever
you actually put it on let me make sure
I'm doing this right because sometimes
it does get a little bit tricky all
right I'm not going to take my shoe off
here it's still GNA work all right so
you go ahead and get right here you try
to go ahead and actually let me lower
this down a little bit go ahead and flip
it and it makes it a whole lot easier
for you to go ahead and get everything
in position and you might have to turn
it a little bit but that's a quick way
to do it you could always you know just
slide it on kind of his personal
preference this is my way I like doing
it so as you can see that Contour is
going kind of with the way your knee is
going to bend right here and that's
going to allow you to be more flexible
so those straight stitched knee sleeves
a straight stitching right so it's going
to go right up the middle right here
right on your joint and that's kind of
going to limit your Mobility a little
bit so if you're looking for some these
sleeves that you can use across Prett
much all your lifts you're going
definitely going to want that Contour
design if you're a competitor looking
for some certified knee sleeves well
guess what they're right here in front
of you and I also think these are going
to be great for anybody who's looking
for some highly versatile knee sleeves
because of that contoured stitching
without sacrificing the compression and
the stability because these are 7 mm
thick now the other hand really just
boils down to personal preference when
it comes to not wanting to purchase
these maybe you don't need this thick of
a sleeve maybe you want the three or the
five maybe you want that straight
stitching really just boils down to your
personal preference
y'all well that's a wrap for today's
review over the iron bull 7 mm knee
sleeves I love the Contour design it's
going to allow your knees to stay pretty
mobile but you're not going to be
sacrificing stability and compression
because they are 7 mm thick and then
plus they're certified by multiple
federations thanks for watching y'all I
hope this video is really helpful and
that I was able to break down everything
there is to know about these knee
sleeves as always stay posted for my
next video but for now head over to
barb. comom cuz we have a full written
article about these knee sleeves that
you'll probably find to be pretty
helpful all you got to do is search
barbend Iron bull 7 mm knee sleeves
review it's going to pull right up for
you and you can read everything I talked
about here today I'll catch youall next
[Music]
time